# **Bridget Shannon**

(904) 568-8032 | bridgetrshannon@gmail.com

Linkedin.com/bridget-shannon | Github.com/bridgetrshannon | bridgetrshannon.github.io/Portfolio/

#### SUMMARY

Full-stack web developer leveraging music education background to build a more inviting and accessible user experience on the web. Recently earned a certificate in full stack development from the University of Central Florida, with newly developed skills in JavaScript, CSS, React.js, and responsive web design. With previous experience as an educator, I'm ready to bring problem solving skills and a creative mindset to developing web applications. My most recent project was a music search application, Audiophyle. On a team of four developers, I created an application that allows users to search for and save their favorite musical artists. This app uses MySQL, JavaScript, Node.js, Express, Bootstrap, and TheAudioDB. I'm looking forward to using my skills as part of a socially-conscious, quality-driven team to build better web experiences for all users.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, ¡Query, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, & Handelbars.js

#### **PROJECTS & APPLICATIONS**

#### **Audiophyle**

github.com/bridgetrshannon/Audiophyle | audiophyle-music-platform.herokuapp.com/

- The Audiophyle application allows users to search for and save their favorite musical artists.
- Developed CSS wireframes, front-end design of all pages, and assisted my team with api routes.
- HTML, CSS, MySQL, JavaScript, Node.js, Express, Bootstrap, and TheAudioDB API

#### **Peckish**

github.com/bridgetrshannon/Peckish | bridgetrshannon.github.io/Peckish/

- The Peckish application helps users search for and discover new and exciting food and drink recipes without having to purchase a cookbook.
- Developed all elements for the Social media and Food Inspiration section and assisted my team with the debugging of our code.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query, MealDB and CocktailDB APIs, UiKit Framework

#### The Burger Place

github.com/bridgetrshannon/Burgers | the-burger-place-1.herokuapp.com/

- The Burger Place is an application that allows users to log their choice of burger, change it's devoured status, or delete it.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL, Node.js, Express, Handlebars and an ORM.

#### **Readme Generator**

github.com/bridgetrshannon/Readme Generator

- The Readme Generator is a command-line application that dynamically generates a professional README.md file from a user's input using the Inquirer package.
- Node.js

#### **Employee Tracker**

github.com/bridgetrshannon/Employee Tracker

- The Employee Tracker application allows the user to view and manage the departments, roles, and employees in their company so they can organize and plan their business.
- Node.js

#### **Team Profile Generator**

## github.com/bridgetrshannon/Team\_Profile\_Generator

- The Team Profile Generator application allows a user to manage information for their team. Using the
  command-line, a user can input their team's information. When the user has completed building the team, the
  application will create an HTML file that displays a nicely formatted team roster based on the information
  provided by the user.
- Node.js

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Safety Harbor Middle School; Pinellas County, Florida

Chorus Teacher & Junior Thespian Co-Sponsor, January 2018 – Present

- Created and implemented daily lesson plans for Beginning Girls Chorus, Intermediate Girls Chorus, Advanced Ladies Chorus, Boys Chorus, Musical Theatre, and Music Technology
- Managed department financials from fundraiser, concerts, and donations
- Accurately maintained records, including student data, purchase orders, and event organizing
- Attended weekly staff meetings with administrators to analyze test score data and work with content area teams to better improve classroom practices
- Consistently received Excellent and Superior ensemble ratings at District and State competitions

## Florida State University, Summer Music Camps; Tallahassee, Florida Assistant Director Night Staff, Instructor, Summers 2016 – 2019

- Supervised a team of 28 night counseling staff
- In coordination with Human Resources, used the website WhenlWork.com to create schedules for my team to ensure full supervision of campers
- Oversaw group mediations between campers
- Conducted bi-weekly meetings with staff and university administrators to analyze the previous week's logistics and identify areas for improvement
- Coordinated recruitment events with university Admissions staff
- Developed lesson plans for and instructed Vocal Diction, Music Appreciation, Musicianship, and Chorus electives

# Palm Harbor University High School; Pinellas County, Florida

Florida State University College of Music Internship, Guest Teacher August 2017 – December 2017

- Created and implemented daily lesson plans for Chorus, Musical Theatre, and International Baccalaureate Music
- Attended weekly staff meetings with content area teams to better improve classroom practices
- Accurately maintained records, including student data and purchase orders

# Florida State University, University Housing; Tallahassee, Florida

Resident Assistant, August 2014 – May 2017

Received Specialization in Special Music Education

- Developed and facilitated programming initiatives for the 6,500 college students living on campus each year.
   Programing topics included: Scholarship, Personal Wellness, Engagement, Appreciation of Difference, and Responsible Citizenship
- Completed 240 hours of Crisis Management training. Topics covered included, but were not limited to, mental health, substance abuse, and intimate partner violence.
- Part of a team that oversaw the safety and wellbeing of 500 residents
- Conducted individual meetings with 57 residents focusing on development, involvement, and identity development

# **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Web Development Certificate; University of Central Florida, Orlando, Florida

Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Expected Completion November 2020
A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery,

Bachelor of Music Education in Choral Music Education; Florida State University, Tallahassee, Florida